
var firebaseConfig = {
  apiKey: "AIzaSyB0TaVem3g2jHi9uMBlQC32453y-ETPNko",
  authDomain: "quiz-app-d20a4.firebaseapp.com",
  projectId: "quiz-app-d20a4",
  storageBucket: "quiz-app-d20a4.appspot.com",
  messagingSenderId: "910281338911",
  appId: "1:910281338911:web:e0a9d1375e29acfccee52a"
};

// Initialize Firebase
var app = firebase.initializeApp(firebaseConfig);



var questions = [
  {
    question: "HTML Stands for",
    option1: "Hyper Text Markup Language",
    option2: "Hyper Tech Markup Language",
    option3: "Hyper Touch Markup Language",
    corrAnswer: "Hyper Text Markup Language",
  },
  {
    question: "CSS Stands for",
    option1: "Cascoding Style Sheets",
    option2: "Cascading Style Sheets",
    option3: "Cascating Style Sheets",
    corrAnswer: "Cascading Style Sheets",
  },
  {
    question: "Which tag is used for most large heading",
    option1: "<h6>",
    option2: "<h2>",
    option3: "<h1>",
    corrAnswer: "<h1>",
  },
  {
    question: "Which tag is used to make element unique ",
    option1: "id",
    option2: "class  ",
    option3: "label",
    corrAnswer: "id",
  },
  {
    question: "Any element assigned with id, can be get in css ",
    option1: "by # tag",
    option2: "by @ tag",
    option3: "by & tag",
    corrAnswer: "by # tag",
  },
  {
    question: "CSS can be used with ______ methods ",
    option1: "8",
    option2: "3",
    option3: "4",
    corrAnswer: "3",
  },
  {
    question: "In JS variable types are ____________ ",
    option1: "6",
    option2: "3",
    option3: "8",
    corrAnswer: "8",
  },
  {
    question: "In array we can use key name and value ",
    option1: "True",
    option2: "False",
    option3: "None of above",
    corrAnswer: "False",
  },
  {
    question: "toFixed() is used to define length of decimal ",
    option1: "True",
    option2: "False",
    option3: "None of above",
    corrAnswer: "True",
  },
  {
    question: "push() method is used to add element in the start of array ",
    option1: "True",
    option2: "False",
    option3: "None of above",
    corrAnswer: "False",
  },
];

var ques = document.getElementById("ques");
var opt1 = document.getElementById("opt1");
var opt2 = document.getElementById("opt2");
var opt3 = document.getElementById("opt3");
var btn = document.getElementById("btn");
var timer = document.getElementById("timer");
var index = 0;
var score = 0;
var min = 1;
var sec = 29;

var interval = setInterval(function () {
  timer.innerHTML = `${min}:${sec}`;
  sec--;
  if (sec < 0) {
    min--;
    sec = 59;
    if (min < 0) {
      min = 1;
      sec = 59;
      nextQuestion();
    }
  }
}, 100);

function nextQuestion() {
  var getOptions = document.getElementsByName("option");

  for (var i = 0; i < getOptions.length; i++) {
    if (getOptions[i].checked) {
      var selectedAns = getOptions[i].value;
      //   var selectedQues = questions[index - 1].question;
      var selectedOpt = questions[index - 1][`option${selectedAns}`];
      var correctAns = questions[index - 1]["corrAnswer"];

      if (selectedOpt == correctAns) {
        score++;
      }
    }

    getOptions[i].checked = false;
  }
  btn.disabled = true;

  if (index > questions.length - 1) {
    Swal.fire({
      title: "Good job!",
      text: ((score / questions.length) * 100).toFixed(2),
      icon: "success",
    });
    clearInterval(interval);
  } else {
    ques.innerText = questions[index].question;
    opt1.innerText = questions[index].option1;
    opt2.innerText = questions[index].option2;
    opt3.innerText = questions[index].option3;
    index++;
    min = 1;
    sec = 29;
  }
}

function target() {
  btn.disabled = false;
}